EMAD AGHAYI

Springfield, MA, emad.aghayi@gmail.com, https://linkedin.com/in/emadaghaei

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with 12+ years in analysis, design, development, testing of various applications (web services, Multi-threaded, microservices, mobile and web). Experienced with all stages of the development cycle for web and mobile projects. Exceptional problem solver with an aptitude for troubleshooting and the ability to quickly master a new skill, technology, or role. Strong background in management and leadership. Proved lead with excellent interpersonal and motivational abilities to collaborative relationships among high-functioning teams. Authorized to work for any US employer.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Back-end: Advanced Knowledge of Java, JavaEE, Microservices, JPA, JTA, JMS, Servlet, Swing, Java Media Framework, Spring (Spring Core, Spring MVC, Spring Boot, Spring Security, Spring Data), and Hibernate; Experience with Nodes.js, Express, Python, Swift, and C#.

Front end: JSF, JSP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, UX, User Experience Testing.

Mobile development: Android, iPhone.

Cloud: Azure, Google Cloud Functions, Heroku Platform.

Automation/Containers: Docker, Kubernetes, Rancher, Tomcat, JBoss, WebLogic, Wildfly, WSO2. Database: Microsoft SQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Firebase, Cassandra, Redis, YugabyteDB.

Test: Junit, Mockito, WireMock, Combinatorial test, Mutation testing (PIT).

CI/CD: GitHub Action, Harness, Jenkins, TeamCity.

Analyzing and Monitoring: Dynatrace, Grafana, SonarQube, SoapUI, JProfiler, JMeter.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer at Thoughtworks

♀ MA,USA

Nov 2021 - Present

Thoughtworks is a leading global technology consultancy that integrates strategy, design and software engineering to enable enterprises and technology disruptors across the globe to thrive as modern digital businesses.

- Design and Build Kroger reward debit card supply chain software.
- Design and migrate from premise to Azure cloud
- Leading two teams at the same time of 10 employees
- * Environment: Java, Microservice, Spring, Azure, Harness, Rancher, Kubernetes, Azure.

Software Development Toolmaker at DevX

♥ VA,USA

Aug 2017 - 2022

DevX conducts experiments on how humans interact with code and design new ways to build software.

- Created several tools and processes to provide better infrastructure to increase the productivity of developers by considering human-centered design
- Researched, designed, and developed the first microtasking web-based IDE (Demo URL)
- Designed and developed a plugin for IntelliJ IDEA, a java-based app for Firebase files, and a python-based app for visualizing data
- Published papers in top venues (Google Scholar URL)
- Mentored undergrad software engineer researchers
- * Environment: Java, Python, API, Spring MVC, Spring Security, Google Firebase, Google Cloud Functions, Express.js, IntelliJ Platform SDK.

- Improved code-search in IntelliJ IDEA. Enabled developers to more rapidly understand how to use a function.
- Design and develop the Cluster Usages plugin to help IntelliJ IDEA users.
- * Environment: Java, IntelliJ Platform SDK, API, Multi-threading, IntelliJ IDEA, GitHub.

Lead Software Engineer at ISC

Dec 2015 - Jul 2017

ISC is an international financial services corporation. It facilitates electronic financial services such as mobile banking, online banking, funds transfers through credit cards, debit cards, and prepaid cards.

- Designed, developed, and maintained a financial mobile banking client-server software with more than 10+M daily active end users.
- Led a development team with eight developers.
- * Environment: Microservices, JavaEE, Hibernate, Spring, Servlets, EJB, Log4j, multi-threading, encryption, Oracle DB, SOAP/Rest Webservices, Weblogic, Wildfly.

Senior Software Engineer at CityDI

Apr 2013 - Nov 2015

CityDI, a financial services corporation, facilitates electronic financial services such as mobile banking, online banking, funds transfers through credit cards and debit cards.

- Developed a service-oriented J2EE multi-tier application to provide a tool to inform people and departments about any event via SMS or email.
- Developed a kiosk terminal for financial banking software. It is enabled by biometric fingerprint, Face recognition, NFC. It had all the daily operations of banks/credit unions in one software on the kiosk.
- Led a development team
- * Environment: JavaEE, Java, Microservices, Swift, Android, Hibernate, Spring, Servlets, JSF, Log4j, WPF, .Net, multi-threading, Oracle DB, SOAP/Rest Web services, Weblogic, IntelliJ IDEA, Debian Linux

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATES

Ph.D. in Computer Science at George Mason University

Aug 2017 - 2022

M.Sc. in IT Engineering at University of Tehran

Aug 2011 - Mar 2014